所以接下来的步骤在这里。
So next steps here.
我们将研究函子。
We're going to look at functors.
所以让我们跳到，让我们保存它，然后
So let's jump over to, let's save that and
转到幺半群 2、幺半群 1、0 索引，当然。
go to monoids 2, monoids 1, 0 indexed, of course.
所以函子是幺半群。
So functors are monoids.
好的，我将交替使用幺半群和半群。
All right, I'm gonna be using monoids and semigroups kind of interchangeably.
我真的很了解串联行为。
I'm really getting at the concatenation behavior.
身份是随之而来的一个非常好的属性。
And identity comes as a very nice property that follows from that.
但大多数时候我们非常关心连接。
But most of the time we care very much about concating.
与身份无关。
Not as much about identity.
但它确实有回报。
But it does pay off.
所以很高兴知道。
So it's good to know.
但我会交替使用它。
But I'm gonna use it interchangeably.
所以我们这里有这些函子，ID。
So we have these functors here, ID.
这是函数式编程课程中的盒子。
This was box in the functional programming class.
它是恒等函子。
It's the identity functor.
它什么都不做。
It just does nothing.
任务捕获异步。
Task capture the async.
要么捕获您将拥有的左侧或右侧，通常是错误。
Either captures the you'll have a left or a right, usually errors.
所以如果我放置一个任务，我会从 ID 开始。
So if I put a task, I'll start with the ID.
身份证很容易看。
ID's easy to look at.
让我们抓住其中一些我们在这里定义的有趣的幺半群。
And let's grab some of these some of these fun monoids that we've defined over here.
所以我们有任何东西，还有空的等等。
So we've got any and all and empty and whatnot.
我们只是把它们扔在那里。
We're gonna just throw them up there.
我们走了。
And there we go.
所以我们有一个总和为 2 的 ID。
So we have an ID of a sum of 2.
我实际上可以用总和为 3 的 ID 连接它。
And I can actually concat that with an ID of sum of 3.
我们应该得到一个五之和的 ID。
And we should get an ID of the sum of five.
所以如果 ID 持有的是幺半群，那么它就是幺半群。
So ID is a monoid if what it's holding is a monoid.
就像说黄油手指悬挂式滑翔机。
Like to say a butter fingered hang glider.
它是一个，而它持有一个。
It is one whilst it holds one.
所以通过事实是 如果它只是一个半群
So via the fact is that If it's just a semigroup,
那么 ID 将是一个半群。
then ID would be a semigroup.
是的，它所持有的东西定义了它的行为。
Right, it's whatever it's holding defines its behavior.
所以我们可以说让我们继续看看这是否真的有效。
So we could say let's go ahead and see if this actually works.
你们都十指相扣。
Fingers crossed y'all.
而且我想我现在必须调用extract 才能将其从ID 中取出。
And I think I have to call extract to get it out of the ID for now.
让我们来看看。
So let's look at that.
或者事实上，让我们不要调用提取物，看看它给了我什么。
Or in fact, let's not call extract and see what it gives me.
节点幺半群一。
Node monoids one.
是的，所以我们得到了这种东西，它是一个恒等函子。
Yeah, so we get this kind of thing, which is an identity functor.
只是很难看。
It's just hard to look at.
所以我们将调用extract。
So we'll call extract.
&gt;&gt; 在这种情况下，extract 与上一堂课中的 full 相同吗？
&gt;&gt; And in this case extract is the same as full in the last class?
&gt;&gt; 完全正确。
&gt;&gt; That's exactly right.
我们得到的是一个对象，这可能是错误的。
And what we've got is an object, which is probably wrong.
让我们来看看。
So let's look at that.
让我们看看我的实现是否错误
And let's just see if I got my implementation wrong of either or
如果只是看起来不对。
if it's just not looking right.
让我们折叠。
Let's do fold.
嘿，让我们引入那个有趣的身份功能来折叠它吧？
Hey, let's bring in that fun identity function to fold it out right?
我们称之为 ID。
We'll call it ID.
我们会做 x 和 x，很酷。
We'll do x and x, cool.
折叠 ID，ID。
Fold ID, ID.
好吧，让我们看看这个是否有效。
All right, let's see if this one works.
好的，这个有效。
Okay, this one works.
我只是搞砸了我的身份功能。
I just messed up my identity function.
实际上，看看这是如何实现的会很有趣。
Actually, this will be kind of fun to see how this is implemented.
让我们来看看我们的类型。
Let's go over to our types.
现在，让我们在混乱中寻找身份。
Now, let's find identity in this chaos.
我们是说，我们持有一些东西，x，看看那个。
And we're saying, we hold something, x, look at that.
我没有编程到接口。
I didn't program to the interface.
[笑] 这就是为什么，我们走了，很酷。
[LAUGH] That's why, here we go, cool.
所以正如我们在这里看到的，
So as we can see here,
我们有一个 ID 将它的内脏与另一个连接在一起，对吗？
we have an ID concating its innards with another one, right?
所以它所做的就是说出我拿着的任何东西，
So what it's doing is saying whatever I'm holding,
将那个与另一个连接起来，然后将其提取出来以获得它的 x。
have that concat with the other one, and extract that out to get its x.
然后我们继续
And then we'll go ahead and
将其保留在 ID 内，因为它在组合下已关闭。
keep it inside the ID because it's closed under composition.
所以让我们把它放回 ID、ID 和
So let's put it back into ID, ID and
那么我们应该可以从这里提取出来。
then we should be able to extract out of here.
我们走了，酷。
There we go, cool.
所以这就是通过接口编程的好处，如果你
So that's the benefit of programming through an interface if you
实际上去做。
actually do it.
所以，我们可以在这里做的另一件事是，让这些堆栈尽可能多。
So, one other thing we can do here is, so these stack as much as we want.
对了，我们可以放一个任务权限的ID[笑]。
Right, we can put an ID of a right of a task [LAUGH].
它只是组成。
And it just composes.
它直接会级联，
It just straight up will cascade,
将 this 所持有的任何内容与 this 所持有的内容连接起来。
concating whatever this is holding with whatever this is holding.
关键是，只要我连接相同形状的东西，
The point is, as long as I'm concating something with the same shape,
如果我们回到那个 gobstopper 的例子，我们采用了所有这些不同的效果
if we go back to that gobstopper example, we took all these different effects and
我们把它做成同样的形状。
we made it into the same shape.
这是一种分层类型。
It's kind of this layered type.
我实际上可以将它与另一件事联系起来。
And I can actually concat that with another thing.
它会打开ID，打开右边，打开任务和
And it will open up the ID, open up the right, open up the task and
将太阳凝聚在一起。
concat the sun together.